Guide to the Fales Family Papers MSS.029
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Family Papers
circa 1620-1966
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales family
MSS.029
68.5 linear feet
4 videocassettes (u-matic)
21 film reels
1 sound discs (lacquer)
2 sound discs (vinyl)
The Fales Family Papers document the history of the family from the 17th- 20th centuries through their correspondence, legal documents, family trees, travel journals, auction catalogs, photographs, and some books from the personal library of DeCoursey and Haliburton Fales. Among the interesting items in the collection are letters from John Adams and Thomas Jefferson, both dating from 1822. Other correspondents include: Andrew Dunlap, Samuel Fales Dunlap, Haliburton Fales, Sr. and Jr., and DeCoursey Fales, Jr.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Arrangement
Series I, II and IV are arranged alphabetically and the remainder are arranged chronologically.
Organized into 6 Series: 1. Fales Family; 2. DeCoursey Fales; 3. DeCoursey and Haliburton Fales Library list; 4. DeCoursey Fales auction catalogs; Series V, DeCoursey Fales, Jr; Series VI, Lyman Law; and three Accretions from 2000, 2001 and 2003.
Biographical Note
The Fales family can claim ancestry back to the Puritan settlers who arrived in New England on the Mayflower. Eventually, the family became centered in Bristol, Rhode Island. Descendants of the Fales family have been variously involved in politics (Andrew Dunlap, 1796-1835), aviation, yachting, philanthropy and other assorted businesses and interests. DeCoursey Fales (1888–1966) collected rare books and manuscripts. In 1957, he donated his collection to NYU in memory of his father, Haliburton Fales. An in-depth description of the family and its history up to 1919 can be found in De Coursey Fales's 'The Fales Family of Bristol, Rhode Island' (Series III, box 6 and 7 of this collection).
Sources: Fales, De Coursey. The Fales Family of Bristol, Rhode Island. Boston: Privately printed, 1919.
Provenance
The Fales Family Papers were acquired between 1957-1997 through generous contributions made by DeCoursey Fales and Haliburton Fales, II. The original portion of the collection, relating to DeCoursey Fales, was acquired sometime after the founding of the Fales Library in 1957. The first donation by Haliburton (December 1996), consisted of the R.B. Taney letter to Benjamin Stone (1836) and three copy books of the late Haliburton Fales Jr. The second donation (March 1997), included three boxes of archival materials from the Fales Family. Subsequent donations were made in 2000, 2001, and 2003. These materials are described at the end of the collection as accretions.
Scope and Content Note
The Fales Family Papers are a part of the Manuscript and Archive Collections at the Fales Library, New York University. The Fales Library is the primary special collections division of the NYU libraries, housing over 170,000 volumes of English and American literature from 1700 to the present. Strengths of the collection include the development of the English and American novel, with an emphasis on the Gothic and the Victorian novel.
The Fales Family Papers is an archive of the personal papers of the Fales family spanning from circa 1626 to 1966. The collection includes correspondence, legal documents, family trees, travel journals, auction catalogs, photographs, and some books from the personal library of DeCoursey and Haliburton Fales. Among the interesting items in the collection are letters from John Adams and Thomas Jefferson, both dating from 1822. Also included is a curious passport of Samuel Fales Dunlap, which included letters of announcement, calling cards, and a French Visa all dating from the year 1846. The collection was sorted by Amber Creger and arranged in an alphabetical and chronological order. Oversized materials from the various series are located in an oversize box at the end of the collection. For a detailed history of the Fales Family, please consult The Fales Family of Bristol, Rhode Island, written and published by DeCoursey Fales, 1919.
An additional gift of material from the mid to late 1800s was added to the collection and is listed at the end of this finding aid as Accretions 2000. The materials were sorted and many docketed by Dorothy Mildred Mitchell Fales. In addition, a gift of Iten Scott (Mrs. DeCoursey Jr.) Fales of material pertaining to DeCoursey Fales, Jr., dating from ca. 1940 to 1957, was added to the collection. This material is listed at the end of this finding aid as Accretions 2001 A. Further acquisitions of materials were processed and listed as Accretions 2001 B. This series includes nineteenth and twentieth century correspondence and photos, ephemera, mementos, and books.
SERIES DESCRIPTION:
Series I: Fales Family: contains three boxes of personal Fales Family documents, which are then divided into three subseries. The files are arranged alphabetically and chronologically. subseries A contains 1 and half boxes of Fales Family correspondence, travel journals, photographs, memorial cards, and scrapbooks. subseries B contains 1 box of Fales Family legal documents including wills, court case manuscripts, account books, leases, receipts, and business records.
Series II: DeCoursey Fales: contains two boxes of files relating to DeCoursey Fales, which are divided into four subseries. The files are arranged alphabetically and chronologically. subseries A contains half a box of DeCoursey Fales correspondence, scrapbooks, photographs, and printed material. subseries B contains half a box of documentation of the various clubs and hobbies Fales participated in, such as; yacht log books, New York Flight Club meeting minutes, Harvard Club, and Masonic Lodge. subseries C contains half a box of items relating to the book, The Fales Family of Bristol, Rhode Island, including correspondence, engravings, and the Dedham Fales family ancestry of Haliburton Fales 2 nd. subseries D contains half a box of items relating to Fales collecting books and the NYU collection. Material includes lecture notes, Fales collection register, and pamphlets produced by NYU about the collection.
Series III: DeCoursey and Haliburton Fales Library List: contains six boxes of books, that were originally from the personal libraries of DeCoursey and Haliburton Fales.
Series IV: DeCoursey Fales auction catalogs: contains fifteen boxes of auction catalogs from the early and mid-twentieth century that were used by DeCoursey Fales to purchase items for his vast manuscript and book collections. The files are arranged alphabetically and chronologically. Some have annotations by Fales.
Series V: DeCoursey Fales, Jr. consists of material pertaining to DeCoursey Fales, Jr., dating from ca. 1940 to 1957.
Series VI: consists of legal contracts, commissions, and receipts relating to Lyman Law's legal practice in early 19th century New London, Connecticut. Also included are Lyman Law's personal letters to his son, William Henry Law, as well as documents relating to William Henry Law's legal practice.
Oversize: Box 28 Contains oversize materials from Series I and II. Box 39A contain oversize materials from accretions received in 2001.
Auction catalogs.; Genealogical tables.; Journals (accounts); Legal documents.; Photographs.; Private libraries (institutions); Correspondence.; Genealogy -- Rhode Island -- Bristol; Dunlap, Andrew, 1794-1835; Dunlap, S. F. (Samuel Fales), 1825-1905; Fales, DeCoursey, 1888-1966; Fales, Haliburton, 1849-1929; Fales, Haliburton, 1919-
- Series I: Fales Family
  - Subseries I.A: Correspondence
    Scope and Content note
    Contains one and half boxes of Fales Family correspondence, travel journals, photographs, memorial cards, and scrapbooks.
    - Bridgham, Eliza Ann(Fales) 1813-1895, correspondence from family. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bridgham, Haliburton, correspondence from Haliburton Fales Jr., 1904. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Campbell, Charlotte(Haliburton), correspondence to family, 1796-99., 1796-1799 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Corse, Catherine(Ketchum), correspondence to Morris Ketchum., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Corse, Lena, correspondence to Grampa Ketchum, 1855. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Corse, Margaret, correspondence to Margaret Parker, 1870. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Dunlap, Andrew 1794-1835, correspondence from John Adams, 1822. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dunlap, Andrew 1794-1835, correspondence as Attorney General, 1834. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Dunlap, Andrew 1794-1835, correspondence as Attorney General regarding resignation, 1835. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Dunlap, Andrew 1794-1835, correspondence from family, 1835. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Dunlap, Andrew 1794-1835, correspondence, 1831-35., 1831-1835 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Dunlap, Andrew 1794-1835, correspondence from Pedro Gilbert, 1834-35., 1834-1835 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Dunlap, Andrew 1794-1835, correspondence from R. B. Taney to Benjamin Stone, 1836. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Dunlap, Andrew 1794-1835, correspondence from Thomas Jefferson, 1822. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Dunlap, Andrew 1794-1835, correspondence to Lady Superior of Unsuline Convent, 1835. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Dunlap, Andrew 1794-1835, newspaper obituaries. (oversize box) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Dunlap family photographs., undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Dunlap, L. A. C. A. (Fales) 1802-1887, correspondence from Sarah Dunlap, 1835-41., 1835-1841 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Dunlap, L. A. C. A. (Fales) 1802-1887, correspondence from Eliza Fales, 1834-52., 1834-1852 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Dunlap, L. A. C. A. (Fales) 1802-1887, correspondence from Haliburton Fales Jr. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Dunlap, L. A. C. A. (Fales) 1802-1887, correspondence from Samuel and Abigail Fales, 1834-42., 1834-1842 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Dunlap, L. A. C. A. (Fales) 1802-1887, correspondence from family. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 23. Dunlap, L. A. C. A. (Fales) 1802-1887, correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Dunlap, L. A. C. A. (Fales) 1802-1887, correspondence to Samuel and Abigail Fales. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Dunlap, Samuel Fales 1825-1905, correspondence from L. A. C. A. Dunlap, 1845-83., 1845-1883 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Dunlap, Samuel Fales 1825-1905, correspondence from family, 1835-87., 1835-1887 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Dunlap, Samuel Fales 1825-1905, certificate as Commissioner of New York State, 1849. (oversize box) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Dunlap, Samuel Fales 1825-1905, French visa, 1846. (oversize box) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Dunlap, Samuel Fales 1825-1905, Harvard papers. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Dunlap, Samuel Fales 1825-1905, U. S passport wallet and contents, 1846. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Fales, Abigail(Haliburton) 1773-1839, correspondence from family, 1792-1835. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Fales, Abigail(Haliburton) 1773-1839, correspondence, 1835. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Fales common place book #1, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Fales common place book #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Fales, Elizabeth Jane(Beale) 1821-1900, correspondence from family,1848-51., 1848-1851 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Fales, Elizabeth Jane(Beale) 1821-1900, correspondence to Harriet Beale. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Fales, De Coursey Jr. 1918-, correspondence from family. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Fales, De Coursey Jr. 1918-, correspondence from De Coursey Fales, 1932-35., 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Fales, De Coursey Jr. 1918-, correspondence from Dorothy Fales(Mitchell), 1933-41., 1933-1941 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Fales, De Coursey Jr. 1918-, correspondence from misc., undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Fales, De Coursey Jr. 1918-, correspondence to family, 1933. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Fales, De Coursey Jr. 1918-, correspondence to friends, 1935. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Fales, De Coursey Jr. 1918-, Invitations., undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Fales, De Coursey Jr. 1918-, School., undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Fales, Dorothy(Mitchell) 1893-1981, correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, correspondence from Joseph Beale, 1853. (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, correspondence from Augusta, Eliza, and Maria Fales, 1833-48., 1833-1848 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, correspondence from Samuel Fales, 1834-39., 1834-1839 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, correspondence from Samuel Fales, 1844-45., 1844-1845 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, correspondence from family. (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, travel expense log, 1844. (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, travel journal, 1843. (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, travel journal, 1843(copy). (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, travel journal, 1844. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, travel journal, 1844. (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, correspondence from family. (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, Columbia College scrapbook. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, Columbia Law School letters, 1873-74., 1873-1874 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, Holland lodge. (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, letter book #1, 1877. (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, letter book #2. (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, letter book #3, 1885. (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, Mystic Mecca Temple certificate of membership,1909. (oversize) (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, travel journal, 1865. (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Fales, Margaret Ketchum(Corse), correspondence from family., undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Fales, Margaret Ketchum(Corse), correspondence to family., undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Fales, Margaret Ketchum(Corse), photo., undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, correspondence from family, 1802-47., 1802-1847 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, correspondence from Haliburton Fales, 1826-1847. (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Fales, Samuel 1848-1892, correspondence from family, 1886. (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Fales, Samuel 1848-1892, memorial cards, 1892. (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Fales, Samuel 1848-1892, party invitations, 1877. (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Fales, Samuel B. 1804-1880, booklet. (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Fales, Samuel B. 1804-1880, correspondence from family. (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Fales, Stephen 1790-1854, correspondence from family, 1844. (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Fales, Susanne Maria 1809-1853, correspondence from family, 1835-47., 1835-1847 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Dunlap, Samuel Fales, 1825-1905, autograph book of legal notes, n. d. (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Haliburton, Willliam 1739-1817, correspondence from Alex Lyon, 1790-92, 1790-1792 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Helman de l'Academie des Arts de Lille en flandre, Assemble Nationale, engraving, 17 (oversize), undated (Box 2, Folder 80a)
    - Ketchum, Morris Burr, correspondence from Morris and Margaret Ketchum, 1842-53., 1842-1853 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - On board ship Sam Fales, log book [186?] (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Sheafe, Abigail 173?-180?, correspondence to ? (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Unidentified letters and notes., undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Subseries I.B: Legal Documents
    Contains one box of Fales Family legal documents including wills, court case manuscripts, account books, leases, receipts, and business records.
    - Beale, Joseph 1774-1841, legal documents, 1848. (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Building contract for Franklin St., Boston, 1874. (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Campbell, Charlot. Will and inventory of estate, 1802. (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Corse, Israel. Court case documents regarding will, 1885. (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Corse, Israel. Will and inventory of estate, 1885. (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Dunlap, Andrew 1794-1835. Will and inventory of estate, 1835. (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Dunlap, L. A. C. A. (Fales) 1802-1887, account book, 1859-73., 1859-1873 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Dunlap, L. A. C. A. (Fales) 1802-1887, assorted legal documents (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Dunlap, L. A. C. A. (Fales) 1802-1887, assorted legal documents. (oversize box) (Box 2, Folder 92a.)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, business records. (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, correspondence regarding mother's finances. (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, correspondence regarding published books. (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, court case exhibits, 1903. (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, newspaper clipping., undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, statement of Haliburton Fales Jr., 1903. (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, statement of Lizzie Tracey, 1903. (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, stenographer's minutes, July 5, 1905. (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, stenographer's minutes, July 12, 1905. (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, stenographer's minutes, October 25, 1905. (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, real estate. (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, stocks. (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Dunlap, Samuel F. 1825-1905, will and inventory of estate. (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Fales, Charles 1789-1875, misc. legal documents. (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Fales, Elizabeth Jane(Beale) 1821-1900, account book, 1900. (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Fales, Elizabeth Jane(Beale) 1821-1900, account book, 1902. (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Fales, Elizabeth Jane(Beale) 1821-1900, misc. legal documents. (oversize box) (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Fales, Elizabeth Jane(Beale) 1821-1900, taxes,1884. (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Fales, Elizabeth Jane(Beale) 1821-1900, will, 1872. (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Fales, Elizabeth christening record from Bury St. Edmunds church, Suffolk, England c. 1620. Mother of James Fales. Gift of Haliburton Fales. (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Fales, George 1818-1873, account book, 1847. (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Fales, George 1818-1873, Cheever and Fales, 1827. (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, account book, 1847. (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, account book, 1848. (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, court case on the will of James Beale, 1848. (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, lease. (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, Sears & Fales, 1836-48., 1836-1848 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Fales, Haliburton 1815-1869, will and estate. (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, canceled checks, 1916-19., 1916-1919 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, custody case documents, 1895. (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1849-1929, custody case documents, 1895. (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1848-1929, F. P. James & Co., 1884. (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1848-1929, Hartshorne & Picabia. (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1848-1929, law practice. (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1848-1929, legal document. (oversize box) (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1848-1929, property documents. (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1848-1929, receipts. (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1848-1929, Tacoma property, 1890-96., 1890-1896 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Fales, Haliburton Jr. 1848-1929, tax receipts, 1875-98., 1875-1898 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Fales, James 1656-1741, will, 1741. (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Fales, Margaret Ketchum(Corse), lawyers fees,1889. (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Fales, Nathaniel 1719-1801, will and inventory of estate, 1834. (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, correspondence concerning will. (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, Fales & Keith, April 25, 1796-May 25,1796., 1796-1796 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, Fales & Keith, June 2, 1796-August 29, 1796., 1796-1796 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, Fales & Keith, Sept. 5, 1796-Dec. 26, 1796., 1796-1796 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, Fales & Keith, 1797-1800. (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, business notes. (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, receipts. (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, property deeds. (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, Sam Fales & Co. ,1811. (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, stocks. (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, tax receipts, 1876-79., 1876-1879 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, will and inventory of estate, 1816. (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Fales, Samuel 1843-1892, W. H. Goadly Co., 1880. (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Fales, Samuel B. 1804-1880, purchases. (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Fales, Samuel B. 1804-1880, will and inventory of estate, 1867. (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Fales, Susan Marie 1809-1853, mortgage, 1837. (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Fales, Timothy 1690-1777, inventory of estate, 1779. (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Fales, Timothy 1690-1777, will, 1777. (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Haliburton, George 1787-1879, will,1841. (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Haliburton, Georgeanna 1849-?, will, 1880. (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Haliburton, Luiana 18?-?, will memo. (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Haliburton, Mary A. 1797-1888, document appointing Haliburton Fales as her attorney,1848. (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Haliburton, Susanna 1817-1899, will. (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - Haliburton, Thomas Chandler 1796-1865, pension. (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - Haliburton, William H. Otis 1808-?, power of attorney, 1818., 1808-1818 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Mason, Jonathan, will, 1831. (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Oldridge, Alethea, will, 1810. (oversize box) (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - Pattason, Fanny, family servant, will, 1893. (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Smith, Abiel 1746-1815, will, 1814. (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Subseries I.C: Fales Genealogies
    Consists of one box containing Fales Family trees and genealogies.
    - Beale, family tree., undated (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Bradford-Fales, family tree. (oversize box), undated (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Bradford-Fales, genealogy., undated (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Coursey, family tree., undated (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Fales, family tree., undated (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Fales & Little, births., undated (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Fales, Samuel 1775-1848, correspondence on family genealogy. (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Haliburton, family tree. (oversize box), undated (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Haliburton, genealogy., undated (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - Halyburton, genealogy from Douglas Peerage., undated (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Otis, family tree., undated (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Scott, Walter Sir, "Memorial of the Haliburtons," handcopied by Samuel B. Fales, 1840. (Box 4, Folder 175)
- Series II: DeCoursey Fales
  - Subseries II.A: Correspondence
    Contains half a box of DeCoursey Fales' (1888-1966) correspondence, scrapbooks, photographs, and printed material.
    - Burns Society., undated (Box 4, Folder 176)
    - Car registration, 1921. (Box 4, Folder 177)
    - College notes., undated (Box 4, Folder 178)
    - Correspondence from Haliburton Fales, Jr., 1914-19., 1914-1919 (Box 4, Folder 179)
    - Correspondence., undated (Box 4, Folder 180)
    - Correspondence to family., undated (Box 4, Folder 181)
    - Correspondence to friends., undated (Box 4, Folder 182)
    - Ephemera., undated (Box 4, Folder 183)